

AHMED HASAN

Deputy Manager - HR (HRIS | Payroll | Recruitment | PMS | ER | HR Opp.)

+92.321.2026204



ahmedhassanchrp@gmail.com



Mehmoodabad, Karachi, Pakistan

Summary

Working experience in Textiles & Automotive & Retail Industry. Strong command on implementation of Oracle and SAP based HR-ERP.

Having expertise in Payroll Management, Recruitment, Job Descriptions, Performance Management, Employee Relation, Full & Final Settlements, & other HR operation & Administrative operations.

Skills

HR Policies | Administrative Management | Compensation & Benefit | Corporate - HR Departments | decision-making skills. | Employee Administration | Employee Engagement | Employee Relations | EOBI | ERP Software | Full & Final Settlement | Health Insurance | HR Consulting | HR Information Management | HR Policies | HR Policy Formulation | HRIS Database Management | HRMS/HRIS | Human Resource Planning | Job Description Creation | Labor Laws | Microsoft Office | Payroll Management | Payroll Processing | Performance Management | Record Keeping | Recruitment & Talent | Staff Management | Time Management

Experience

Oct 2019 - Present

Deputy Manager - HR (HRIS | Payroll | Recruitment | PMS | ER | HR Opp.) AFGHAN CARPETS, Karachi, Pakistan

â‼¢ Manage & provide HR support on full spectrums of HR activities/services, including Payroll Management, Recruitment & Talent Management, Training & Development, Performance Management & Employee Relations. â Preemployment verification, employment agreements & amendments, personnel file maintenance & set up, benefits, administration, payroll input, attendance tracking, data management in HRIS, HR data reporting, off-boarding, etc. A¢®A¢ Responsible for delivery of Country KPIs (Workday KPI, Payroll KPI, Recruitment KPI, etc.) A¢IA¢ Train and improve HR Staff capabilities ensuring efficiency in HR operations. A¢®A¢ HR Policy custodians, ensuring compliance and control on HR processes and practice. â2¢ Responsible that HR Operations team standard are set, that efficient & effective HR processes are in place and described. â P¢ Managing employee engagement and communication, deploying necessary communication plan and ensuring employee engagement activities are carried out to achieve the intended objectives. ̮Ţ Manage successful performance and implementation of assigned HR projects, with regards to Employment Records, Benefit programs, Performance and Compensation Management, Recruitment, Payroll, (HR) systems, etc. ̮A¢ Act as a liaison between employees, other departments and vendors to resolve issues received through the HR Ops team and facilitate processing. A¢\(\textit{?}\)A¢ Monitor, maintain and process HR related information in internal HR Systems & databases and / or files, ensuring high quality data, whilst maintaining required privacy.

Apr 2015 - Oct 2019

Asst. Manager HR - HRIS | Payroll | Recruitment | HR Operations AL-HAJ FAW MOTORS, Karachi, Pakistan

HRMS (ERP) Administrator/ Dashboard Reporting Recruitment: Payroll / Comp. & Benefits Management: Employee Relations: Full & Final Settlements: HR Policies & Compliance: Personnel Records Management: OTHERS... â (\$\text{Support HR Operations}\$) team. Covering full range of HR activities and supporting a total workforce of over 1000 employees. (Permanent, Contractor, apprentices and Daily Wagers). â2¢ Issue various letters to the employees (Appointment Letters, Confirmation letters, Experience certificates etc.) â2¢ Maintain the employee status from probation to confirmation, increments, appraisal and final settlement and recording the events in the software. â Ich Preparing and maintaining employment personnel records related to events such as hiring, termination, leaves of absence, and job transfers â 2¢ Conducting Exit interviews for all employees leaving the organization, analysing the reasons and submitting a report to the CEO and Head of HR for Full and Final Settlement. â2¢ Facilitates in the development and maintenance of HR manuals, processes, forms, guidelines etc. â2¢ Developing and maintaining organization chart. â (Maintain the HR Annual Budget assigned to the department by the management. â∑¢ Track and execute employee confirmation process within 90 days of new hire. â (Uphold documentation for audit purpose such as updated Org charts, JD review & Employee Files

Mar 2007 - Dec 2015

HR Executive

Soorty Enterprises (Pvt.) Ltd., Karachi, Pakistan

Operations & Payroll Management

- Responsible for Leaves and Attendance system management as well as preparing the monthly Payroll for all employees
- Responsible for Time Management System for all employees and In charge of account Management of Limton Company regarding Time Information System.
- Handling the HR Confidential data (Employees Salary, Summary Sheet, and Employee Information Sheet etc.), review, update and maintain.
- Responsible for Employee Separation process; Resignations, terminations, exit interviews and general clearance.
- Ensuing maintenance and complete records in the personal files of staff.
- Periodically coordinating with the Group HR for records and associated matters.
- To assist the HR Manager to deliver a pro-active, progressive, innovative and customer-focused recruitment and administration function. Coordinate with HR team to implement recruitment, operational and training strategies / policies
- Prepare monthly recruitment, leaves, benefits, turnover, exit interviews, apparel HR operational reports
- Facilitate posting/transfer cases e.g Transfer/Transfer with Promotion, Unit wise Transfer or department wise Transfer, Transfer or Promotion within the budget or additional budget, (initiated based on business requirement and approved as per authorization on matrix
- Coordinate with internal Audit and finance department for piece rate, fort nightly, contractor and cash disbursement process.
- Maintain disciplinary action record e.g charge sheet, warning letter, show cause, domestic i inquiry, dismissal letter and follow termination procedure as per the policy.

? Recruitment

- Responsible for recruitment activities &maintaining the HR Resume Database.
- Social media coverage to create job postings and advertisements.
- Responsible for drafting all new contracts and employment Agreements, Appointment Letters, Confirmation Letters,
- Employee Relation & Employee induction.
- Weekly Recruitment Updates to Management.

Education

Pakistan Institute of Management
Certification, PGD HRM
HRM, Labour Laws, Industrial Relations
Completed

NED University of Engineering & Technology
Certification, CHRP (Certified HR Professional)
HRM
Completed

University of Karachi
Bachelors in Commerce, B.Com

Languages

Urdu English
Expert Intermediate

Commerce, Economics